Guide to the Stanford University, Humanities Honors Program, Theses
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Humanities Honors Program, theses
1949-2010
SC4-4211
Stanford University. Humanities Honors Program
63.5 Linear feet
Senior honors papers by undergraduates in the Humanities Honors Program.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
The collection was received via administrative transfers from the Humanities Honors Program. Additional theses were transferred from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Information about Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of senior honors papers by undergraduates in the Humanities Honors Program.
Access Terms
Education, Humanistic.; Humanities; Student papers.
Collection Contents
- Theses, pre-1990
  - Abrams, William F., Pride and prejudice: the characterization of Robert Cohn in The Sun Also Rises., 1976 (Box 1)
  - Adle, Maria, Sadegh Hedayat et son ouevre., 1976 (Box 1)
  - Adler, Lisa Miriam, Resistance in Literature of the Holocaust as Seen in the Works of Hannah Senesh, Moshe Flinker, and Abraham Sutzkever., April 15, 1983 (Box 21)
  - Aiken, Carolyn, An analysis of the content, presuppositions, and values inherent in the Honors Program in Humanities at Stanford., 1952 (Box 1)
  - Ainars, Vizma, Self-revelation in the confessions of Augustine and Rousseau., 1966 (Box 1)
  - Aladjem, David R. E., On reforming the social pact., 1981 (Box 1)
  - Alkire, David, The humor of Mark Twain and William Faulkner. (Box 1)
  - Allen, Dave, Sir Thomas More: the transcendence of a Christian humanist., 1977 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Gregory P., And a child shall lead them: an analysis of the Vonnegut protagonist., Spring 1973 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Thomas John, Wherein we play: the world as theater in As You Like It and King Lear., Spring 1973 (Box 1)
  - Almas, James P., Catholic evolutionists and the Church: 90 years to prohibition., 1972 (Box 1)
  - Almas, Jane M., Charles Darwin: author in conflict., 1973 (Box 1)
  - Amamoto, Florence, Quest for coherence: T. S. Eliot; Four Quartets and Theodore Roethke; North American Sequence., April 1972 (Box 1)
  - Amberg, Joshep Paul, Ambiguous Authorship in Don Quixote and One Hundred Years of Solitude., 1979 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Einar W., A Study of Musical Improvisation., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Kent Lee, The poetry of Theodore Roethke: a craft for revelation., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Laurie Jane, Challenging the norm: the dialect questions in the works of Gadda and Pasolini., 1977 (Box 1)
  - Andreasson, Katrin, Camus' use of myth in L'Etranger and La Chute., May 1, 1983 (Box 21)
  - Andrus, Margaret, Art as communication - the painter's contribution to society., 1949 (Box 1)
  - Anstedt, Ted, the star: the stud: and the I; a critical study of the ns2:role of absolute operative ideals in man's approach to reality., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Ardzrooni, Edward S. Jr., What makes a history-book history., 1955 (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, James, William Blake's The Gates of Paradise: The Power of Imagination., 1970 (Box 1)
  - Austin, James L., Red men and white eyes: frontier American attitudes towards the Plains Indian and their effect on Indian-White relations., 1972? (Box 1)
  - Axelrad, David M., The concept of soul and survival after death in Rabbinic Judaism., 1972 (Box 1)
  - Back, Anthony, Constructing reality: Multiple perspectives in Ulysses and The Waves., 1980 (Box 1)
  - Bacon, Robert Allen, Tillich and Cassirer on religious symbolism., 1969 (Box 1)
  - Baer, George Webster, A Student's Approach to Toynbee., 1957 (Box 1)
  - Bahrych, Lynn, The absolution of Eve., 1969 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Nan, Crime and revolution: A study in social violence., 1960 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Claire, The modern literary reception and representation of Friedrich Holderlin., June 1985 (Box 21)
  - Bandurraga, Peter L., Jazz Time., 1966 (Box 1)
  - Baran, Kennet William, Jr., A perspective on psychohistory., 1978 (Box 1)
  - Barker, Meredith, Introduction to heroism., 1970 (Box 1)
  - Barksdale, Brent E., Pacifism and democracy in Colonial Pennsylvania., 1961 (Box 1)
  - Barry, Daniel, Evolution and the Adaptive Value of War., 1969 (Box 1)
  - Barton, Robert Joyce, The Rebel., 1955 (Box 1)
  - Bauer, Karen L., The Implied Nabokov., 1980 (Box 1)
  - Beard, Marian H., The Idiot by Fyodor Doestoevsky: six characters., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Beard, Michael, Progress in the style of Nikos Kazantzakis: A Study of his prose fiction., 1966 (Box 1)
  - Becker, Daniel F., Shakespeare as "Cheerful Greek": a Nietzschean perspective on Hamlet, King Lear, and Antony and Cleopatra., 1977 (Box 2)
  - Becker, Laurose, One City: A Preface to City Planning., 1951 (Box 2)
  - Becker, Terrence C., The nature of meaninglessness: an examination of the Book of Job, King Lear, and Notes from the Underground., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Beckwith, Lee G., John Keats' romantic love: a psychological perspective., April 1984 (Box 21)
  - Behrman, Suzan, Martin Buber and the Jewish Bible., 1962 (Box 2)
  - Benett, Cathy, faith, reason, and the modern synergism: can story and system "live happily ever after"?., 1975 (Box 2)
  - Bennet, Betty, An analysis of the american reception of Sartre's plays., 1954 (Box 2)
  - Bergstrom, Phillip, the views of Nietzsche and Wagner on decadence., 1975 (Box 2)
  - Berke, Tricia Margot, Euripidean ethics - a positive response to the implications of an amoral cosmos., 1971 (Box 2)
  - Bernard, Mary Ann, Liberty and the liberal arts: Vergerio and Sturm., 1975 (Box 2)
  - Berry, Robert W., The Freedom of Science--A Contemporary Question., 1958 (Box 2)
  - Bickford, Nabcy, Russian Nihilism in three Nineteenth-Century Novels., 1955 (Box 2)
  - Binkerhoff, George Everett, Prosperity and Character in Buber and Newman., 1972 (Box 2)
  - Birk, Judith, Kokutai: Religio-political ideal of Japan., 1974 (Box 2)
  - Birnie, Elizabeth, Translation and Illustraion: Six Interpreations of Gargantua.., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Blacker, Deborah, Chuang Tzu and Sartre: a question of parallels., August 1981 (Box 21)
  - Blakly, Christopher W,, The Characters of Felllini's I Vitelloni, La Dolc Via, 81/2 and Juliet of he Spirits: Problems, and the tentaive naur of their resoluions., 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Blank. Diana R., In Defiance of Meaning: The Aesthetic of Becke's Billingual Text., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Blosser, William, The Revoluion of 1958 in France., 1966 (Box 2)
  - Bogden, Paul, Three Philosophies of Mind: A Comparative Critique., 1975 (Box 2)
  - Bohnhoff, Henry M., Polyarchy in Japan: The Role od Group Orienaion in a Democraic Society., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Bolger, Nacy, the Creative Sructur Within: An Analyis on Jung's Collecive Unconscious., 1977 (Box 2)
  - Borwn, Sharon Lee, D.H. Lawrence and the New Religion., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Boushey, Annette, The Shape and Consistency of Coyote in Mythology of the West Coas Indians., 1971 (Box 2)
  - Bowditch, James R., Loneliness: A Theme in the Works of Edwin Arlingon Robisnson and Eugene O'Neill., 1958 (Box 2)
  - Bowman, Robera, Truths and Counter-truths: William B. Yates and the artisic self - image., 1975 (Box 2)
  - Boynton, Laura, Morning: Excellent and Fair., 1981 (Box 21)
  - Brenzel, Logan Elaine, Rober Musil and Thomas Mann: Reconcilliatiin of the Subjective and Objective Aaspects of Modern Conscious Experience Through Experimentation., 1982 (Box 21)
  - Bressier, Dan, Perspecivism in the Though of Friedrich Nietzsche and Chaung Tzu: Social Perspectives and Byond., 1977 (Box 2)
  - Briesen, Frances Huneke von, The Outward Comment: The Inner Conflict. An Essay on Goya and Picasso., 1960 (Box 2)
  - Brodell, Anne rayne, The Humanism of Albert Camus and Sarvepallli Radhakrishnan., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Brooks, Robert N., Towards Orpheus: The Psychology of Conflict in the Drama of Tnnessee Williams., 1964 (Box 3)
  - Broughel, David B., Dag Hammarskjold: A Study of His Public and Private Sides., 1973 (Box 3)
  - Broun, Leroy A. IV, Maning and Freedom in the Symphonies of Beethoven., 1995 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Barbara Sue, Women and Love: A Critical Analysis of Egalitarian Possibilites in the Lives, Works and Philisophies of Jean-Paul Sartre and Simone de Beauvoir., 1974 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Cornelia E., Narrative and Desire in Anais Nin's Cities of the Interior., 1973 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Elixabeth Marin, On Tragedy or How o Seperate the Goat-Songs from the Sheep-Songs., 1969 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Leslie W., Bolivar, San Martin and the Army., 1966 (Box 3)
  - Buch, Michael J., The False God...., 1965 (Box 3)
  - Bun, Mary Lucia W., The Marxist Realism Debate: Brecht v. Lukacs., 1983 (Box 21)
  - Burke, Frederick Raymond, Marxism, Science and Aestheics in Bertol Brecht's Lben des Galili., 1981 (Box 3)
  - Burrows, Eric, Wilsonianism: the failure of Nationalism., 1982 (Box 21)
  - Busch, Janine, Rhythm in the Waves., 1978 (Box 3)
  - Bushwall, Stephen James, Archibald McLeish's J.B.: the Evolution of an Art Form., 1982 (Box 21)
  - Bussanich, John R., The Artist's Searc for Salvatin in herman Broch's Death of Virgil., 1973 (Box 3)
  - Byrne, Elizabeth, Eastern adnWestern Interpretations on Non-Violence: Ghandi and Tolstoy., 1970 (Box 3)
  - Calvo, Ahmed Venancio, The Problem of Knowledge in Nietzsche's Thought: A Pradoxical Epistemology., 1977 (Box 3)
  - Cameron, James K., Ideology and Utopia: The Breakdown of Consensus in Purian and Jacobin Movements., 1974 (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Elizabeth, Tow Yet One: Views on Love from D.H. Lawrence and Wrich Fromm., 1978 (Box 3)
  - Carey, Mell C., A Criique of Robert M. Hutchins' Attack on Contemporary American Higher Education., 1956-1957 (Box 3)
  - Carlson, Joan M., The Ecumenical Sisterhood of Mary, Its Way and Mission., 1959 (Box 3)
  - Caro, Ehel E., Music and Thomas Mann., 1958 (Box 3)
  - Carpenter, Russell B., The Concept of Self in Socrates and the Buddah., 1964 (Box 3)
  - Carpenter, Susan, "The Sheltering Conception": An Approach to he Poetry of Wallace Stevens and Robert Frost., 1970 (Box 3)
  - Carpenter, William, Vers Le Theatre Interieur: Elements of Mallarme's Total Art Form., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Carter, William B, An Interpretation of the Fiction of Franz Kafka., 1957 (Box 3)
  - Cattermole, George, An Examination of Some Principle Theses in th Philosophy of C.I. Lewis., 1967 (Box 3)
  - Cavanaugh, Kevin, The Man of the Infinite Illusions: Tom Lingard and the Malaysian Trilogy of Joseph Conrad., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Chandler, Tom, The way of Inquiry: Montaigne's Resolution of a Dilemma., 1976 (Box 3)
  - Chaplin, Phillip T., Martin Hiedegger's use of language for answering die Seinefrage., 1977 (Box 3)
  - Charnas, Charles Nahaniel, Turgenev's Magnificent Achievement., 1981 (Box 3)
  - Chase, Mary Jane, Marguerite D'Angouleme: A Brief Examination of her Political Power and Religious Convictions., 1977 (Box 3)
  - Chavez, Anna M., Four works by Madame Marguerite Duras., 1975-76 (Box 3)
  - Chen, Nancy Nu-Chen, Foundations of traditional medicine: conceptions of the human body, disease, and health in the hippocratic corpus and the Huang Ti Nei Ching Su Wan., 1985 (Box 21)
  - Chu, Milton Wesley, Freedom and fate in Lord Jim and Crime and Punishment., April 15, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Chueh, Jane, The art of healing: China and the West., 1980 (Box 3)
  - Cilley, Earl, Aspects of Roman Satiric verse., 1958 (Box 3)
  - Clark, William S., Aspects of Political TV., 1956-57 (Box 3)
  - Clifford, Gregg R., Idea contra art: the first step., 1977-78 (Box 3)
  - Clurman, Irene, Surrealism and the painting of Matta and Magritte., 1970 (Box 3)
  - Coe, Robert, Netting the fin: image and vision in Virginia., May 1972 (Box 3)
  - Coldren, Joan, John Dewey: aesthetic theory., 1952-53 (Box 4)
  - Collings, Gina Michelle, Indianism in Brazilian romanticism., 1976-77 (Box 4)
  - Conant, Ardis, Michelangelo's Last Judgment., 1969 (Box 4)
  - Conroy, Carol, The human condition: dawn or twilight., 1960 (Box 4)
  - Cordes, Lester G., Edward Jenner: The man, His age, Reflections., 1968 (Box 4)
  - Corrigan, Margaret, Marxism and the pragmatic intelligence: a study of the works of Sidney Hook., 1976 (Box 4)
  - Crandall, Michael Mark, Anselm's Ratio: the personality of his religious thought., 1978 (Box 4)
  - Crandall, Robert A., Josiah Royce's concept of community and its relation to the American experience., April 1972 (Box 4)
  - Crowley, Paul G., In the face of evil: a critical appraisal of the thought of Teilhard de Chardin., Spring 1973 (Box 4)
  - Culver, Willis L., Nature and human nature in the fiction of William Faulkner., 1956 (Box 4)
  - Cummings, John T., Jr., Actual limitations to conflict in American politics and the American perception of the ns2:role of the constitution., 1974 (Box 4)
  - Cummins, Carolyn, A critical study of cultural relativism., 1952 (Box 4)
  - Currie, Shirley Ann, A comparison of the philosophies of education of John Dewey and Robert Hutchins., 1956-57 (Box 4)
  - Cutler, Roberta, Hegel and Nietzsche: cultural relativity and impartiality., 1977 (Box 4)
  - Dampier, Katie, The return of the individual: genuine individuality in Kierkegaard and Nietzsche., 1976-77 (Box 4)
  - Danford, Mary, Geez, Doc, I guess it's all right but what the hell does it mean?" An undergraduate's introduction to W. C. Williams' Paterson., 1978 (Box 4)
  - Dann, Mary Elizabeth, The spiritual world of Eugene O'Neill., 1955 (Box 4)
  - Daugherty, Robert, freedom and enslavement in major works of Twain and Hemingway., April 1972 (Box 4)
  - Davies, Todd Richard, Analogy., June 11, 1985 (Box 21)
  - Davis, Angela Joy, An introduction to the poetry of Luis Cernuda with analyses of selectd poems., June 1, 1983 (Box 21)
  - Davis, Lisa A., A woman's vision: Maria Luisa Bombal and Virginia Woolf., Spring 1984 (Box 21)
  - Davis, Mark H., The transcendental ego: three perspectives., 1977 (Box 4)
  - Davison, Mary C., Artistic creation., 1957 (Box 5)
  - Della Pietra, Richard A., Aristotle and Cassirer on mind, knowledge, and imagination., 1974 (Box 5)
  - Dempsey, Jed, Artificial intelligence and the metaphor of mind., September 17, 1983 (Box 21)
  - DeWolf, David K., Eschatology in the philosophies of Nicolas Berdyaev and Gabriel Marcel., 1971 (Box 5)
  - Diefendorf, Patricia Lane, Departures from realism in representation of social reality: a study of five modern german dramas. (Box 5)
  - Diefendorm, Jeffry M., Rosa Luxemburg and Friedrich Ebert: a comparative study of the concept of revolution., 1967 (Box 5)
  - Dietler, Michael D., Celtic Ireland: reconstruction and analysis., 1974 (Box 5)
  - Diffenbaugh, Ann R., Henry Adams: his study of Americna statesmen., 1976 (Box 5)
  - Donovan, Theresa, Rhetoric and vision in Pope's Epistle to Cobham., 1976 (Box 5)
  - Doudoroff, Michael Johnf, Literary nationalism: a study of the Mexican novel., 1961 (Box 5)
  - Dowler, Janet, A Modern Doctor Faustus and the German Nation., 1960 (Box 5)
  - Drace, Richard Lee, A thematic illustration of Dietrich Bonhoeffer's Wordly man., 1969 (Box 5)
  - Dudli, Monika A., Pushkin, Mickiewica and the overcoming of Romanticism., 1976 (Box 5)
  - Dudrey, John R., Imagination in ascendance: Charles Baudelaire and the origin of pure art., 1970 (Box 5)
  - Duggan, Charles H., Andavo a fare l'America: the story of the emigration from Barga, 1850-1924. (Box 5)
  - Duvall, Ronald I., The condition of man according to the Traibhumikata., 1974 (Box 5)
  - Earl, Marie L., Use of myth in One Hundred Years of Solitude., 1978 (Box 5)
  - Early, Dennis R., The ecological method and the English garden., 1978 (Box 5)
  - Edwards, Sally Gressens, The concept of evil in Karl Barth and Friedrich Schleiermacher., 1974 (Box 5)
  - Egger, David, A nation's dilemma., 1958 (Box 5)
  - Elliott, Patricia, The Concept of Zion. (Box 5)
  - Ellis, Jonathan C., Philosophical ideas of music in works by William Shakespeare: the music of men's lives., 1978 (Box 5)
  - Erbit, Nancy, Painters and patriotism in the American Revolution., 1947 (Box 5)
  - Erickson, Laura, Musical concepts in the poetry in T. S. Eliot., May 5, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Ernst, Carl W., Plotinus and Nagarjuna: a comparative study of the mythical and theocretical symbolism of the psychic dynamisms of transcendence in the context of the Platonic and Buddhist traditions., Spring 1973 (Box 6)
  - Evans, Christine Ann, Women in Love and Ulysses: the manly and womanly streams of being., 1975 (Box 6)
  - Fair, William Robert III, The influence of Cicero on Leon Battista Alberti: a historical, social and ideological discussion., June 7, 1985 (Box 21)
  - Falletta, Jane, The virtuous Man: a study of Dante's Virgil in the Divine Comedy., Spring 1983 (Box 21)
  - Fan, May, Ideological foundations of Chinese medicine., March 24, 1983 (Box 21)
  - Farrell, Ann C., Television Communication with Practical Application to Philosophy., 1953 (Box 6)
  - Fazzino, Gary Patrick, Towards an expression of God's unity: a look at the theological work of Rabbi Shenur Zalman of Liadi., 1974 (Box 6)
  - Fellmeth, Robert C., The utopian vision of Aldous Huxley., 1967 (Box 6)
  - Finley, Bruce B., American Industrialism and Utopia., May 1984 (Box 21)
  - Fitzgerald, James M., An essay on Black Power., 1967 (Box 6)
  - Flosi, Kathleen S., Levels of interpretationin three children's stories: Saint-Exupery's Le petit prince, Carroll's Through the looking glass, and Van Eeden's De kleine Johannes., 1974 (Box 6)
  - Foster, Melissa, The arts: a priority for society., May 12, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Fox, Marybeth, Outside urbanization and the end of an era in Chase County, Kansas; a personal approach., May 1972 (Box 6)
  - Francesconi, James L., Bonheffer's "Modern Christian", and Nietzsche's "Zarathustra"., 1974 (Box 6)
  - Frank, Carole Ann, Escape from freedom - German style and American style., 1956 (Box 6)
  - Frankel, Mary William, Vision-ary writing: Le bleu du ciel., May 1983 (Box 21)
  - Franklin, Barbara, Conflict and Contradiction in Post-Revolution Irish Drama., 1964 (Box 6)
  - Fraser, Jeffrey L., The ox and the lion: a view of moral liberty and responsibility through the eyes of Andre Gide., April 19, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Fratessa, Jeanne, C. S. Lewis' Theological science fiction., 1959 (Box 6)
  - Fredericks, Craig Allen, An historical analysis of the concept of alienation from Karl Marx to Jean-Paul Sartre., 1977 (Box 6)
  - French, Mary Ellen, The relationship of an artist's personality to his art work: Vincent Van Gogh and Paul Gauguin., 1959 (Box 6)
  - Fuller, G., Sartre and freedom., 1964 (Box 6)
  - Fylstra, Mary Beth, Menno, Numster and Martyrdom: The Anabaptist struggle for religious liberty., 1980 (Box 6)
  - Gantz, George R., Samuel Beckett and analytical philosopy., Spring 1973 (Box 6)
  - Geeslin, Keith B., The views of Alexis De Tocqueville and James Bryce on liberty and equality., 1975 (Box 6)
  - Giannini, Leana, Cavour and Lincoln: Comparative aspects of the definition of a nation., 1979 (Box 6)
  - Gibson, Jonathan David, Poe and Baudalaire: One's Gift to the Other., 1979 (Box 6)
  - Gibson, Paul Maclay, Postwar German literature: from tragedy to satire and beyond., 1976 (Box 6)
  - Gifford, Dunn Jr., Reactions to Capitalism in Stendhal's Le Rouge et le Noir., 1985 (Box 21)
  - Girvin, Matthew, Aesthetic constellations: a study of visual art and Williams' poetics as semiological systems., 1987 (Box 6)
  - Godat, David M., Wittgenstein's Vienna and Handke's prose: Representational crises., June 1984 (Box 21)
  - Gomperts, Constance, John Donne - His Search for Divine Security. (Box 6)
  - Gonzalez, Richard A., Anatomy and structure: a study of the theories of Northrop Frye and Claude Levi-Strauss., Spring 1973 (Box 6)
  - Goodpasture, Hew, Human experience and ethics: a study of the thought of Albert Camus., 1965 (Box 6)
  - Goodwillie, Susan R., An exploration into the worlds of Eugene Ionesco and.. .., 1963 (Box 6)
  - Gordon, Michael Robert, The way to chaos: Nietzsche and National Socialism., 1961 (Box 6)
  - Gould, Stephanie, The literary symbol in the modern world., 1967 (Box 6)
  - Grafstein, David, Themes of heroism and homosexuality: death in the novels of Yukio Mishima., 1975 (Box 7)
  - Grauf, Claudia, Martin Luther's image of God., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Green, Garrett, A kingdom not of this world: a quest for a Christian ethic of revolution with reference to the thought of Dostoevsky, Berdyaev, and Camus., 1964 (Box 7)
  - Green, Virginia, Existentialism and the theology of Rudolf Bultmann., 1962 (Box 7)
  - Greenley, James R., Reinhold Neibuhr and the nature of man., 1966 (Box 7)
  - Gregorian, Vartan, Toynbee and Islam., 1958 (Box 7)
  - Grobman, Alan, A knot in time: the reparations and agreement between West Germany and the State of Israel., 1977 (Box 7)
  - Guerrant, Helen L., Existential Skepticism in Joseph Conrad's Moral Code., 1960 (Box 7)
  - Haas, Margaret P., The American search for sacred Japan two literary perspectives: Lafcadio Hearn and Gary Snyder., August 1971 (Box 7)
  - Hahne, Marjorie Helen, Chaucer's Use of the Confession., 1962 (Box 7)
  - Hampton, Roger K., Religion and the creative affirmation of Friedrich Nietzsche., 1970 (Box 7)
  - Hancock, Steven Lee, The tragicomedy in The Secret Agent and As I Lay Dying., April 1972 (Box 7)
  - Hardy, Sarah Boykin, Reasoned musics: an exploration of the poetry of Mina Loy., Spring 1984 (Box 22)
  - Harrington, Maggie, Destiny half-fulfilled: Franklin D. Roosevelt as a charismatic leader., 1961 (Box 7)
  - Hart, Sally, Immanent and Transcendent types of natural law: their political consequences., 1965 (Box 7)
  - Harvey, Phyllis, The ideals of the education of the family in fifteenth-century Florence., 1949 (Box 7)
  - Harvie, Thomas, The Romantic as Catholic: G. K. Chesterton and Evelyn Waugh., 1965 (Box 7)
  - Hayashi, Leslie Ann, Aesthetics: the art of art from Romanticism to Modernism., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Hearn, Jerry, Bertolt Brecht: the committed artist., 1966 (Box 7)
  - Hempel, Tom, Words of Being., 1981 (Box 22)
  - Herlach, Mark D., The scientist as policy-maker: J. Robert Oppenheimer, 1945-52., April 1972 (Box 7)
  - Hermann, Donald, Blue Stockings on the New Deal Line., 1965 (Box 7)
  - Herold, Kathryn A., Narrative Technique in Three Modern "Love Stories": The Good Soldier, Lolita, and Second Skin., 1980 (Box 7)
  - Herrmann, Anne C., The concept of androgyny in Virginia Woolf and E. M. Forster., 1974 (Box 7)
  - Hess, Linda, A solitary perfectionist: Winters and literary criticism in the twentieth century., 1964 (Box 7)
  - Hetenyi, Agnes Jeanie, Classicism and Romanticism reconsidered., 1965 (Box 7)
  - Hilitz, Jacqueline, Machiavelli, A Realist?., June 7, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Hines, Sally H., Towards an Understanding of Witchcraft., 1969 (Box 7)
  - Hitchcock, Eva, Berthold Brecht and the epic theater., 1956 (Box 7)
  - Hite, Jerry, Two tellings of God's word., March 1972 (Box 7)
  - Hodder, Elizabeth, Characterization in the novels of John Steinbeck., 1959 (Box 8)
  - Hoffman, Ann, The form of a modern tragicomedy: Waiting for Godot in the tradition of twentieth century European anti-theatre., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hoffmeister, Charles, Attitudinal Influences on Birth Control Practice in the United States., 1969 (Box 8)
  - Hogeland, Lisa Maria, An edge of history: the implicit feminism of Doris Lessing's The Four-Gated City. (Box 8)
  - Hoglund, J. Steven, The Style of European Diplomacy, 1860-1864., 1966 (Box 8)
  - Holman, Cynthia A., Dissolution of self in the Sea of Fertility tetralogy., May 24, 1982 (Box 22)
  - Holme, Howard K., The case for legalized abortion., 1967 (Box 8)